<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on Pierre-Francois Loos&#39; research webpage</title>
    <link>https://pfloos.github.io/WEB_LOOS/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on Pierre-Francois Loos&#39; research webpage</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>loos@irsamc.ups-tlse.fr (Pierre-Francois Loos)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>loos@irsamc.ups-tlse.fr (Pierre-Francois Loos)</webMaster>
    <atom:link href="https://pfloos.github.io/WEB_LOOS/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Funding</title>
      <link>https://pfloos.github.io/WEB_LOOS/funding/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>loos@irsamc.ups-tlse.fr (Pierre-Francois Loos)</author>
      <guid>https://pfloos.github.io/WEB_LOOS/funding/</guid>
      <description> ERC CNRS LCPQ FERMI NEXT NanoX UPS </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>People</title>
      <link>https://pfloos.github.io/WEB_LOOS/people/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>loos@irsamc.ups-tlse.fr (Pierre-Francois Loos)</author>
      <guid>https://pfloos.github.io/WEB_LOOS/people/</guid>
      <description>Group Members Pierre-Francois Loos (group leader, CV) Follow @TitouLoos&#xA;Directeur de recherche (HDR)&#xA;Laboratoire de Chimie et Physique Quantiques&#xA;Université de Toulouse, CNRS, UPS, France&#xA;Researcher ID: A-1103-2010&#xA;ORCID: 0000-0003-0598-7425&#xA;Telephone: +33 5 6155 7339&#xA;E-mail: loos@irsamc.ups-tlse.fr&#xA;Fabris Kossoski (Postdoc, ERC) Yann Damour (PhD student, ERC) Antoine Marie (PhD student, ERC) Collaborators Anthony Scemama&#xA;CNRS research engineer (Laboratoire de Chimie et Physique Quantiques, Toulouse, France)&#xA;Michel Caffarel&#xA;CNRS senior researcher (Laboratoire de Chimie et Physique Quantiques, Toulouse, France)</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>https://pfloos.github.io/WEB_LOOS/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>loos@irsamc.ups-tlse.fr (Pierre-Francois Loos)</author>
      <guid>https://pfloos.github.io/WEB_LOOS/publications/</guid>
      <description>2024 137. State-specific coupled-cluster methods for excited states,&#xA;Y. Damour, A. Scemama, D. Jacquemin, F. Kossoski, and P. F. Loos.&#xA;J. Chem. Theory Comput. (submitted). 136. Neutral electronic excitations and derivative discontinuities: An extended N-centered ensemble density functional theory perspective,&#xA;F. Cernatic, P. F. Loos, B. Senjean, and E. Fromager.&#xA;Phys. Rev. B (submitted). 135. Can GW handle multireference systems?,&#xA;A. Ammar, A. Marie, M. Rodríguez-Mayorga, H. G. A. Burton, and P.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Research</title>
      <link>https://pfloos.github.io/WEB_LOOS/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>loos@irsamc.ups-tlse.fr (Pierre-Francois Loos)</author>
      <guid>https://pfloos.github.io/WEB_LOOS/research/</guid>
      <description>Research interest I am currently a full-time CNRS senior researcher at the Universite Paul Sabatier (Toulouse, France). I am part of the Laboratoire de Chimie et Physique Quantiques (UMR5626) within the THEO group.&#xA;ERC Consolidator grant (No. 863481): Processes related to electronically excited states are central in chemistry, physics, and biology, playing a key role in ubiquitous processes such as photochemistry, catalysis, and solar cell technology. However, defining an effective method that reliably provides accurate excited-state energies remains a major challenge in theoretical chemistry.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Talks</title>
      <link>https://pfloos.github.io/WEB_LOOS/talks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>loos@irsamc.ups-tlse.fr (Pierre-Francois Loos)</author>
      <guid>https://pfloos.github.io/WEB_LOOS/talks/</guid>
      <description>Oral communications 64. CIPSI: selected configuration interaction methods for ground and excited states,&#xA;IQTC meeting 2023, Barcelona, Spain (September 2023).&#xA;63. A similarity renormalization group (SRG) approach to GW,&#xA;3rd Quantum International Frontiers 2023, Lodz, Poland (June 2023).&#xA;62. CIPSI: selected configuration interaction methods for ground and excited states,&#xA;TREX workshop on electronic structure methods for strong correlation, Lodz, Poland (April 2023).&#xA;61. A similarity renormalization group (SRG) approach to GW,</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
