<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on Pierre-Francois Loos&#39; research webpage</title>
    <link>https://pfloos.github.io/WEB_LOOS/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on Pierre-Francois Loos&#39; research webpage</description>
    <generator>Hugo 0.125.0</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://pfloos.github.io/WEB_LOOS/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Funding</title>
      <link>https://pfloos.github.io/WEB_LOOS/funding/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://pfloos.github.io/WEB_LOOS/funding/</guid>
      <description> ERC CNRS LCPQ FERMI NEXT NanoX UPS </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>People</title>
      <link>https://pfloos.github.io/WEB_LOOS/people/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://pfloos.github.io/WEB_LOOS/people/</guid>
      <description>Group Members Pierre-Francois Loos (group leader, CV) Follow @TitouLoos&#xA;Directeur de recherche (HDR)&#xA;Laboratoire de Chimie et Physique Quantiques&#xA;Université de Toulouse, CNRS, UPS, France&#xA;Researcher ID: A-1103-2010&#xA;ORCID: 0000-0003-0598-7425&#xA;Telephone: +33 5 6155 7339&#xA;E-mail: loos@irsamc.ups-tlse.fr&#xA;Marios Petros Kitsaras (Postdoc) Mauricio Rodríguez-Mayorga (Postdoc) Antoine Marie (PhD student, ERC) Loris Burth (PhD student) Collaborators Anthony Scemama&#xA;CNRS research engineer (Laboratoire de Chimie et Physique Quantiques, Toulouse, France)&#xA;Michel Caffarel&#xA;CNRS senior researcher (Laboratoire de Chimie et Physique Quantiques, Toulouse, France)</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>https://pfloos.github.io/WEB_LOOS/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://pfloos.github.io/WEB_LOOS/publications/</guid>
      <description>2025 156. Parquet theory for molecular systems. I. Formalism and static kernel parquet approximation,&#xA;A. Marie and P.-F. Loos,&#xA;J. Chem. Phys. (submitted). 155. Complex absorbing potential Green’s function methods for resonances,&#xA;L. Burth, F. Kossoski, and P.-F. Loos,&#xA;J. Chem. Theory Comput. (submitted). 154. Fully analytic nuclear gradients for the Bethe-Salpeter equation,&#xA;J. Tölle, M.-P. Kitsaras, and P.-F. Loos,&#xA;J. Phys. Chem. Lett. (submitted). 153. The QUEST database of highly-accurate excitation energies,</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Research</title>
      <link>https://pfloos.github.io/WEB_LOOS/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://pfloos.github.io/WEB_LOOS/research/</guid>
      <description>Research interest I am currently a full-time CNRS senior researcher at the Universite Paul Sabatier (Toulouse, France). I am part of the Laboratoire de Chimie et Physique Quantiques (UMR5626) within the THEO group.&#xA;ERC Consolidator grant (No. 863481): Processes related to electronically excited states are central in chemistry, physics, and biology, playing a key role in ubiquitous processes such as photochemistry, catalysis, and solar cell technology. However, defining an effective method that reliably provides accurate excited-state energies remains a major challenge in theoretical chemistry.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Talks</title>
      <link>https://pfloos.github.io/WEB_LOOS/talks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://pfloos.github.io/WEB_LOOS/talks/</guid>
      <description>Oral communications 75. Green&amp;rsquo;s function methods for quantum chemistry,&#xA;QVEST XXV, Ringberg castle, Germany (Sep 2025).&#xA;74. Green&amp;rsquo;s function methods for quantum chemistry,&#xA;Technical University of Denmark, Department of Chemistry, Copenhagen, Denmark (Dec 2024).&#xA;73. Excited-state-specific functionals of the asymmetric Hubbard dimer,&#xA;Workshop on Quantum Theory: Foundations and Extensions of Density-Functional Theory, Oslo, Norway (Dec 2024).&#xA;72. Green&amp;rsquo;s function methods for quantum chemistry,&#xA;11th Triennial Congress of the International Society for Theoretical Chemical Physics, Qingdao, China (Oct 2024).</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
